so in this video I'm going to attempt to
drill down into the question of what is
game B it seems to me like this game B
key concept series is not complete
without an attempt to do that so a
couple of qualifications though before I
get started first of all let me just be
clear that this is not any kind of
official game B position right I think
such a thing would be a logical
absurdity anyway but just to be clear
this is just me talking right secondly
I'm not actually going to answer the
question what is game B let me also say
that up front I guess more what I'm
going to be answering is the question of
why is it impossible to answer the
question of what is going be something
like that
it's also worth
highlighting kind of a paradox about
this in that on the one hand game B is
this brand new thing right movement in
game a for 12,000 years or whatever and
game B is a brand new thing but at the
same time game B is is and always has
been going on right the rest of the
world is playing it game B is just us
stuck in game a right every ecosystem
every you know level of organization in
nature is already playing game B so in a
very real sense game B doesn't need to
be designed and constructed it just
needs to be allowed to happen sort of
thing we just need to get out of the way
and let it happen I think one thing
which is probably fair to say again
about game beers it'll figure out a way
to close all of its loops nature closes
all of her loops and so game B will
somehow or other figure out a way to
extract from nature in such a way as not
to debase her and then to reinsert our
waste into nature in such a way that she
can process it well the first part of
the answer to the question why is it
impossible to talk about game people why
is it impossible to say what is game B
is that it is a whole new thing I mean
it's a completely different thing it is
a fundamentally ontologically different
way of organizing society and going
about doing things and so given that we
are running game a code and are stuck
with game a cognitive architecture it is
almost impossible to see game B from our
current vantage point the best we can
ever hope for is to get like a fleeting
glimpse of what it might feel like there
was once a dream that was wrong you
could only anything more than there that
feeling right there that's probably as
close as we can get to
understanding what game B is and as soon
as you know when you do get that
embodied sense as soon as you try and
trap it in the restraints of language
it's gone again right because language
is essentially code rights lines and
lines and lines of linear code and we
process that at the reason level at the
bottom of a key would call the
propositional level and and we reside
game a resides entirely almost in the
propositional layer and it neglects
almost completely the perspectival the
participatory and the procedural levels
of knowing and so you know game B is
going through somehow figure out a way
to reincorporate that much more embodied
sense of knowing in the world
I mean game B is gonna have to solve all
of the same problems that game a solves
right it's gonna have to solve the
problem of how can large numbers of
people collaborate with each other it's
gonna have to solve the problems of
feeding everyone clothing everyone
housing everyone distributing water
distributing energy distributing other
resources you know all all of that kind
of stuff it's also going to have to
solve the problems of how can people
actually find meaning and fulfillment
and purpose and a sense of you know
place and being well held by the society
in their lives game a has failed in many
ways to solve those kinds of problems
and it also has to solve all of these
problems without producing the all of
the externalities that game a produces
the corruption the pollution the
in-group out-group the conflict you know
all of that kind of stuff so game B is
gonna have to solve the same set of
problems the game a solves plus a larger
set of problems plus without producing
all of the externalities and so you
start to get some idea of just how far
beyond the parameters of game a game B
must be and of course there's going to
be new needs and new wants emerges the
Excite as a society of owls and gets
more complex and game B has to be able
to accommodate that as well without
breaking and so if game a is a march
right getting from one place to the next
place to the next place to the next
place setting a goal and going for it
setting a goal and going for it
so if game a is a march then game B is a
dar
is not about setting a goal and reaching
it it's about you know a holistic
interactive expansion of capacity in a
in in a complete and whole manner and so
you know I you can see I'm stumbling
over my words here because I'm trying to
get across something which AI haven't
fully conceptualized myself and B which
is ungettable in language anyway and so
somehow or other gain B is going to
bring together all of those needs which
need to meet which need to be met in the
context of the reality of living in
nature and with elegance and with beauty
and with
fully conscious participation will bring
all of that together in harmonious
relationship this is why it's a dance is
not a March it's a dance it's forever
changing forever responsive to the
changing needs and the changing
circumstances and the changing
environment and so on so yeah that's
that's I hope some sense of why it is so
very difficult to answer the question
and one final thing is if it's
impossible to answer the question game B
is then what the hell are we all doing
talking about game B right
I mean if it's impossible to design if
it's impossible to make it then what the
hell are we doing it and that's a very
reasonable question and in order to
attempt to answer that I'm going to as I
so often do fall back on an analogy that
Jordan Hall Youth is namely that of a
human baby right and so when two parents
bring a baby into the world the baby is
analogous to gain B right you have
brought into the world on its own
without you know without a space in
which to develop that you know the
zygote has absolutely no chance of
surviving in the outside worlds in a
like manner little pockets of game B
that spring into the world are very very
quickly stamped out by game a they're
either co-opted or bought or whatever
and and they disappear very quickly and
so what we in the game be community if
you like and I'm more and more hating
the name by the way but anyway that's
that that's that's another story what
week all we can be doing is create a
womb if you like for that as I go to
develop safely in and so that's what I
think the role of game beers should be
is humbly acknowledging that they don't
know what the fuck game B is don't know
what it looks like and rather
[Music]
in the same way that parents are
completely in service to the unborn baby
right they have no idea what's going on
in the womb there they simply provide a
safe environment or mother
I guess it's a safe environment for the
zygote to develop in and then once it
emerges into the world once again it is
helpless right it can't do anything on
its own it requires help as well but it
but it has to also develop into its own
thing right it can't be directly can't
be told what it must be it must be what
it will be so yeah on the one hand it's
ferociously protecting it but on the
other hand it is absolutely standing
back and letting it be what it will be
with the minimum of interference and
that I feel is the best that we can do
and in order to do that we need to on an
individual level expand our own
capacities in our own ability to
experience the world in a more embodied
and less in our heads kind of way we
need to keep networking and forming
relationships and coming up with ideas
and then just release all that and let
game be whatever it's going to be
develop on its own I mean it's gonna be
this whole I seems to me to be a little
pretty low probability thing but it's
gonna be all of this stuff all of these
ideas all of these networks all of these
people all of these ideas all of this
stuff just swimming around swimming
around swimming around and then one day
possibly maybe it's all gonna cheat come
together and
game be is is locked in right so that's
it really this game B is both miles and
miles away over the horizon but it's
also you know right here right in front
of our faces so let's hope that it
clicks into place one day and in the
not-too-distant future and yeah keep
playing thanks for watching bye